ANTHONY DRANE UX DESIGNER

EXPERIENCE

BEcoME Education // Manly

*UX/UI Designer (Short-Term Contract), February 2018*Working with a UX lead, designing high-level interface concepts for a career-education web-app which sits within a wider workshop experience, considering a range of personas and learning objectives.

• Stakeholder interviews, persona development, journey mapping, heuristic evaluation, sketching, wireframing and documentation.

ProAuto Group // Sydney

UX Consultant, November 2017-Present

Designing a mobile application to supersede existing motor dealership procedures, support the road-to-sale & provide insightful and meaningful data to dealers & manufacturers.

• Stakeholder & user interviews, internal procedures & systems review, process flowcharts, competitive analysis, feature prioritisation to MVP, design studios, wireframing, prototyping, user testing, service blueprinting, business model canvas and presenting.

City Water Technology // Gordon

UX Consultant, November 2017

Designed a business development & content strategy for CWT's website, reframing services within client needs. Provided innovative conceptual mockups with an implementation plan.

• Stakeholder & client interviews, surveys, competitive analysis, affinity mapping, assumptions & hypotheses, ideation, feature prioritisation, sketching, design studios, information architecture, wireframing, usability walkthroughs and presenting.

Nine Entertainment Company // Artarmon

Non-Linear Editor (News), February 2015-Present

- Designing & editing lead stories, packages, features, and overlay to high standards for quick-turnaround on national news broadcasts.
- Working collaboratively and independently, solving creative storytelling problems with journalists and producers.
- Leading morning shifts; ensuring work is assigned, feasible, at high standards and published before deadlines.

Media Exchange Operator, September 2013-January 2015

 Conducted various operational duties around the ingestion, organisation and monitoring of incoming & outgoing media, dealing with complex routing tech in a fast-paced environment.

2MCE Regional Community Radio // Bathurst

News Cadet (Journalist & Reporter), June 2012-July 2013

- Independently produced, wrote and presented back-to-back live community news bulletins, daily, to Central-West NSW.
- Sourced news, designed rundowns, conducted interviews, wrote stories to format and operated professional hardware & software.

EDUCATION

General Assembly // 2017

• User Experience Design Immersive (UXDi18)

Charles Sturt University // 2011-2013

• Bachelor of Communications (Journalism)

Self-Directed, Online Learning // 2014-2017

- Front-End Development FreeCodeCamp (2016)
- Object Oriented Programming P1 University of Helsinki (2015)
- Inspiring Leadership Through Emotional Intelligence Case Western Reserve University, Coursera (2014)
- Learning How to Learn UC San Diego, Coursera (2014)

SHORE School // 2009

Australian Tertiary Admissions Rank 92.3

PROFILE

Hey, I'm a Sydney-based UX Designer with a background in Media & Journalism. I believe user-centred, research-backed design is responsible for sustainable business and facilitates social progress. I'm motivated to fail fast, cheap and early, as well as investigate and collaborate with as many stakeholders, users & designers as feasible to get the right design before getting the design right.

CONTACT

) 0428 581 147

anthonycharlesdrane@gmail.com

in linkedin.com/in/anthony-drane

anthonydrane.solutions

SKILLS

- Business & Market Analysis
- User Research
- Research Synthesis & Strategy
- Flows, Scenarios & Journey Maps
- Concept & Function Maps
- Ideation & Collaborative Design
- Sketching, Wireframing & Prototyping
- Usability Testing
- Service Blueprinting
- Writing & Presenting
- Project & Time Management

TOOLS

Master: Sketch, Balsamiq || Pen & Paper || Velocity ERX, Adobe Premiere Pro Intermediate: InVision, Anima, Omnigraffle || HTML, CSS, Javascipt || InDesign, Photoshop, Illustrator, Final Cut Pro, Microsoft Visio

Beginner: Axure || JQuery

ACTIVITIES

- Runner for 'Getaway', TropFest Film Festival Entrant (2018)
- SXSW Conference, Interactive & Film, Texas (2017)
- Mentor to Junior Radio Cadets, 2MCE (2013)
- Director of 'Forty,' Winner CSU BATS Wingman Festival's Short Film Competition (2012)
- Volunteer Graphic Designer, Project Futures (2011)

INTERESTS

- Short Films, Documentaries & Videography.
- Philosophy, Psychology & Futurism.
- I play guitar, read excessively, love travel, hike & meditate.